Hertford, SG14 1DA

07756197985

rory\_94@live.co.uk

# Front-end developer

Portfolio: https://roryeddleston.co.uk/

GitHub: https://github.com/roryeddleston

# **Summary**

Versatile frontend developer with 3+ years of professional experience building scalable apps and websites. I love writing clean, maintainable code and collaborating with other developers and teams. Currently focused on React/Redux, TypeScript, Tailwind and API's but always keen to learn any new tech. I'm seeking a role where I can continue learning while contributing to meaningful projects.

## Skills

TypeScript, React / Redux, React native, CSS / SASS / Tailwind, API's, Git / GitHub, Gatsby.js, Sanity CMS, SQL, Shopify, Photoshop, Figma, Excel

## **Employment History**

## Front-end developer - Ignition, Hatfield Heath

JUN 2021 - DEC 2024

- Took ownership of the in-house React Native app, fixed bugs and added all new features that were requested.
- Built responsive e-learning courses using the React framework and tools like Lectora and SmartBuilder.
- Created reusable React components that were used across multiple courses reducing the development time significantly.
- Delivered countless polished pixel perfect courses whilst collaborating with designers and content writers. Always received great feedback.
- Al ambassador researched and implemented the latest Al tools on courses. Al translation specialist and tech support for many video translation projects created using Synthesia and HeyGen, saving clients loads of time and money.
- Tech support for live events for both excel spreadsheets and our in-house app.
- Helped set up ecommerce store using Shopify and Liquid.
- Progressed from junior to mid-level within 18 months.

## Data analyst - Credit Benchmark, London

SEP 2018 – JAN 2020

- o Wrote SQL queries and R scripts for internal reporting and external client analysis.
- Led bespoke data investigations, ensuring a high degree of data quality, investigating any variances.
- Maintained and created many excel spreadsheets (v-lookups, pivot tables etc.) to be used for meetings and further analysis.
- Worked closely with Research, Product and Development teams to help fix bugs and look at ways to improve.

#### Volunteer English teacher - Trishuli Rafting, Nepal

NOV 2017 - JAN 2018

- English teacher responsible for teaching 3 different ability groups, everyone progressed well
- Assisted with rafting tours and maintenance of the camp during the day and taught lessons in the evening.
- Helped many of the guides with functional English that was necessary for their jobs through bespoke lessons.
- o Taught some young kids English that had not had a formal education before.

## Education

# Harvard CS50 and many other programming courses

#### Accounting & Finance BSC - Swansea University, Wales

SEP 2013 - AUG 2016

- Completed modules in management accounting, financial accounting, investment banking and graduated with a 58.47% average.
- Additional modules in Entrepreneurship and SAGE.

#### **TEFL, Saint George International, London**

AUG 2017 - SEPT 2017

- Qualified to teach English as a second language after completing an intensive 1 month in-person course.
- Taught actual students from day 1 and completed many related assignments including learning Indonesian.
- Received excellent feedback and made life-long friends. Developed the ability to talk in front of many people at once.

#### Ashmole School, Southgate, London

A-levels in Maths, Biology and Economics.

### Interests

- Travelling I've been to over 30 countries, mainly for hiking.
- Photography channel creativity whilst travelling.
- Football childhood Newcastle supporter.
- Pokémon I have a large vintage collection.
- Reading both fiction and non-fiction.

#### References

\* Available upon request (former Managing Director, Creative Director and Lead Developer all available)